<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jcr:root xmlns:sling="http://sling.apache.org/jcr/sling/1.0" xmlns:cq="http://www.day.com/jcr/cq/1.0" xmlns:jcr="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/1.0" xmlns:nt="http://www.jcp.org/jcr/nt/1.0"
    jcr:primaryType="cq:Page">
    <jcr:content
        cq:lastModified="{Date}2021-07-29T22:55:41.033+05:30"
        cq:lastModifiedBy="admin"
        cq:template="/conf/yogaholics/settings/wcm/templates/yogaholicstemp"
        jcr:primaryType="cq:PageContent"
        jcr:title="Blogs"
        sling:resourceType="yogaholics/components/structure/page"
        navTitle="Blogs"
        pageTitle="Blogs">
        <root
            jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
            sling:resourceType="wcm/foundation/components/responsivegrid">
            <responsivegrid
                jcr:created="{Date}2021-07-19T17:27:15.060+05:30"
                jcr:createdBy="admin"
                jcr:lastModified="{Date}2021-07-19T17:27:28.172+05:30"
                jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                sling:resourceType="wcm/foundation/components/responsivegrid">
                <contentfragment
                    cq:styleIds="[1627532710932]"
                    jcr:created="{Date}2021-07-29T22:53:44.886+05:30"
                    jcr:createdBy="admin"
                    jcr:lastModified="{Date}2021-07-29T22:54:43.714+05:30"
                    jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="yogaholics/components/content/contentFragment"
                    displayMode="multi"
                    fragmentPath="/content/dam/yogaholics/content-fragment/blog2"
                    text="                    Title                                            THE HOUSE OF TWO YEARS            &#xa;&#xa;                        Author                                            By: AnnMarie Roselli            &#xa;&#xa;                        Description                                            &#xa;&#xa;Vito and Carmella defied age in such a way that pretending they’d live forever was easy. My parents were entering year two in a house I’d badgered dad into buying. Sort of. It had taken years of imploring him to sell their big home in Pennsylvania—a lake house with a steep gravel driveway, too many decks, and tremendous upkeep. Though mom relished living on the water and her morning swims, she’d been ready to relocate for some time. In the end, it was more dad’s age that bullied him into buying the townhouse eight minutes from my home in Orange County, New York. And, as in every previous home, mom’s brilliant smile would burn away the dark spots created by dad and his unequivocally fierce temper—a temper that often let loose above his otherwise contemplative nature.&#xa;&#xa;Before my parents moved into the house in Pennsylvania, they’d lived in many other houses. Our family home in northern New Jersey was a ranch-style house which harbored room to run, but never enough rooms to hide in. There were years that ranch turned silent at 6 p.m. when dad walked through the front door after a long day in New York City. Those same years I tried sneaking peeks at the FBI-issue weapon holstered at his hip before he stashed it away. During intolerable adolescent spans, table setting and dinner cleanups pervaded our lives. Years of sweating out report cards and awkward boyfriend introductions passed inside those busy kitchen walls. There were endless Saturdays of facing mom’s chore list written on yellow legal paper. And every second weekend of the month, dad’s big fist slammed the kitchen table because mom forgot to record a few checks into the checkbook log. There were weeks we learned how to ride bicycles and months we learned how to parallel park. Sunday services and bargaining with mom every Christmas Eve to avoid midnight mass were predictable occurrences. And for two decades, despite dad’s mad roaring, a parade of boisterous relatives and happy celebrations arrived.&#xa;&#xa;Before settling in New Jersey, where our youngest brother was born, we’d been a family on the move. As a new agent, dad went where instructed and his young family followed. There was a different house in a different place for five of mom’s six pregnancies. After I was born—daughter no. three, we moved to Monterey, California for six months so dad could learn Sicilian at the Berlitz school. He mapped the way west to east with each move finding a suitable home for our arrival. Often pregnant during relocations, mom moved with bodacious purpose. Any complaints she may have had melted in the fire of her spectacular smile—a smile, I’d grow to unabashedly compare to the occasional comet.&#xa;&#xa;My parents chose Pennsylvania after the New Jersey nest emptied. They pinpointed the area closest to where their first grandchildren would be born. In Lake Ariel, Pennsylvania, dad and mom blueprinted and built their new home and their new life. They embarked on intercontinental adventures, visited their Italian relatives, accessed highways to spend time with family, friends, and took in Manhattan—their birthplace. For eighteen years, they appreciated waking to a rippling sunrise over the boat dock in their backyard.&#xa;&#xa;At eighty-four years of age, dad finally agreed to sell their home in Lake Ariel, and to relocate closer to me. Once settled in New York, mom, with the smile of sunshine and voice of song, filled the townhouse with life. She doted on her children and grandchildren. She filled most days of their social calendar with traveling and entertaining. She was a voracious reader and taught conversational Italian at the local library. She participated in morning exercise classes and walked with neighbors. I even picked her up several days a week to go swimming at the YWCA. Wherever she went—Carmella, now eighty, was affectionately called Millie.&#xa;&#xa;Most mornings, my visits to mom and dad’s townhome required descending their basement stairs where I’d find dad madly pedaling on his exercise bike. He’d offer me a goofy grin and continue pedaling amidst an ocean of balled white. Since his nose had taken to excessive dripping, he often dispatched tissue artillery. He biked to Latin rhythms, Dean Martin, and Tony Bennett. A stalwart son of Italian immigrants, he didn’t care for Frank Sinatra because, according to him, Sinatra didn’t sing enough Neapolitan songs. Dad enjoyed recounting his many childhood tales—one favorite was working on papa’s ice truck at the tender age of seven. He danced to Glen Miller at weddings and nurtured a lifelong crush on Lena Horne. He traveled alongside mom and their social calendar. And like mom, he was a voracious reader. Several times a month he drove his convertible Mustang from New York to a Pennsylvania casino to best poker players sixty years his junior, all with the gumption and grit of a man named Vito.&#xa;&#xa;One day, I entered the house of two years to find an oversized lawn bag sitting near the entrance. It was bulging with retired files, FBI magazines, Hemming’s Motor News, and used legal pads. I used my entire body to drag the bag out the door and heave it into the garbage can. Dad, who was planning to use his hand truck, reprimanded me for risking my back health. A week after a lawn bag, filled with items kept for decades, was discarded, I watched a paramedic team struggle  to revive an eighty-six-year-old man who’d died in his sleep. The medics didn’t know this man. If there was any way for that iron-willed figure to go upright, he’d have done so. As dad’s body bounced beneath resuscitation equipment for nearly an hour, I could hear him yelling that very morning because the water heater had broken.&#xa;&#xa;Mom didn’t want to live in the townhouse without dad. Before she officially moved into my home, the woman who never blocked dying in on her brightly filled calendar pages suffered a major stroke. My eight-minute drive across town became a 50-minute drive to a New Jersey rehab. While mom was there, the contents of her townhome was emptied—furniture, dishes, clocks, and framed memories were passed down. The house of two years sold in one week’s time. After six months of rehab, mom was transported to my home to live in a room retro-fit with medical equipment. Much as we all tried, much as mom’s star-studded smile never waned, she never improved, and after a year, the gut-wrenching decision was made to move her into a long-term nursing facility.&#xa;&#xa;It was nearing the year and a half anniversary of the nursing home I was always anxious to reach when the pandemic arrived. Covid restrictions placed me outside her window where I could still see the brilliant smile she offered every day until she was no longer able. Mom smiled through nearly a year of window visits, glass embraces, and drive-thru coffee hand-delivered by aides or security guards. She contracted Covid mid-December and died beneath her last roof several weeks later.&#xa;&#xa;I find myself trying to remember the many homes I’ve lived in. Whenever I attempt to summon the print of a wallpaper or the fruit bowl on a kitchen table, the handsome faces of my parents sitting down to pasta Sundays appear. I feel mom’s smile and hear her singing Ave Maria. I sense dad’s piercing eyes and see his exercise bike grin. I remember a father and mother who cherished family and friends. I recall two people who embraced life and lived it well. Now that my own children are grown, my husband and I are selling our house of 18 years to find a smaller place to call home. I pray that our daughter and son remember with fondness each imperfect home that love built to keep them safe.&#xa;&#xa;&#xa;&#xa;"/>
                <contentfragment_202492029
                    cq:styleIds="[1627532710932]"
                    jcr:created="{Date}2021-07-29T22:53:50.831+05:30"
                    jcr:createdBy="admin"
                    jcr:lastModified="{Date}2021-07-29T22:55:06.274+05:30"
                    jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="yogaholics/components/content/contentFragment"
                    displayMode="multi"
                    fragmentPath="/content/dam/yogaholics/content-fragment/10-easy-poses-for-beginners"
                    text="                    Title                                            10 Easy Poses For Beginners            &#xa;&#xa;                        Author                                            By: Gurudev Ravishankar            &#xa;&#xa;                        Description                                             &#xa;&#xa;Right from its origins from about 5000 years ago, yoga has now got a worldwide appeal - its significance and benefits appreciated and proven through scientific studies and practices; its profundity obvious when we see the smile that it offers to those health conscious - be it in terms of physical fitness and a calm, serene mind or through attainment of higher states of consciousness.&#xa;&#xa;Our yogic journey began the day we set our foot on Earth. The kick, crawl or walk of a baby are postures so fascinating; the rhythm of their breaths and their joyous presence brings forth the natural yogis that we were all born as.&#xa;&#xa;Yoga for beginners is all about connecting to that yogi in us, to remind us of the wonder poses that we are all familiar with. This wonderful inheritance of our ancient tradition has a multi-fold effect on us. It helps us to increase our awareness; to be in the present moment, with a calm relaxed state of mind, while making our body flexible and healthier.&#xa;&#xa;So, get ready with your yoga mats and enjoy these wonder poses of yoga.&#xa;&#xa;10 Easy Yoga poses for beginners&#xa;&#xa;Whether you are a beginner, an intermediate or an expert, it is advisable to begin your yoga routine with warm-ups and Sukshma Vyayam (gentle exercises). Few minutes of warm-ups make the tendons more flexible, while Sukshma Vyayam relaxes the body. Once through, you can perform the following sequence of easy-to-do yoga poses for beginners&#xa;&#xa;Seated forward bend (Paschimottanasana)&#xa;&#xa;Warrior pose (Veerabhadrasana)&#xa;&#xa;Cat pose (Marjiarasana)&#xa;&#xa;Child pose (Shishuasana)&#xa;&#xa;Bending backward (Ardha chakrasana)&#xa;&#xa;Forward bend (Hastapadasana)&#xa;&#xa;Chair pose (Utkatasana)&#xa;&#xa;Yogic sleep (Yoga Nidra)&#xa;&#xa;Butterfly pose (Baddha konasana)&#xa;&#xa;Angle pose (Konasana)&#xa;&#xa;&#xa;&#xa;"/>
                <contentfragment_107091946
                    cq:styleIds="[1627532710932]"
                    jcr:created="{Date}2021-07-29T22:53:57.273+05:30"
                    jcr:createdBy="admin"
                    jcr:lastModified="{Date}2021-07-29T22:55:23.754+05:30"
                    jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="yogaholics/components/content/contentFragment"
                    displayMode="multi"
                    fragmentPath="/content/dam/yogaholics/content-fragment/yogablogs"
                    text="                    Title                                            HUMANS NEED TREES            &#xa;&#xa;                        Author                                            By Dez Hill            &#xa;&#xa;                        Description                                            &#xa;&#xa;Numerous people in this world have encountered some form of conflict in their life. How these conflicts are dealt with varies from person to person. Many people have traumatic incidents that they endure also, which can cause a disorder called PTSD (post-traumatic stress disorder). The traumatic events that lead to post-traumatic stress disorder are usually so overwhelming, and frightening that they would upset anyone. When your sense of safety and trust are shattered, it’s normal to feel crazy, disconnected, or numb, and most people do.&#xa;&#xa;Let’s explore different ways to deal with PTSD. Self- soothing activities is the most popular way to help keep your emotions under control. If you are unfamiliar with what self-soothing activities are here is a quick summary for you. Self-soothing activities are a source of decreased arousal, pleasurable sensations and calming feelings. They are characterized by: slow, gentle or rhythmical movements; softness in texture, tone and hues; quietness in volume. They include but are not limited to the following: • Calming breathing • Gentle holding and rocking • Calming self-talk • accessing calming sensations: e.g., warm baths and showers, warm drinks, soft textiles (blankets, bed socks, soft toys, hot water bottles), calming music, soft lighting walking, gardening or swimming therapeutic process.&#xa;&#xa;These activities are an incredible way to deal with what symptom’s you may be feeling in that moment; but I want to explore a different route. Let’s think outside the box; trees.&#xa;&#xa;A symbiotic relationship exists between trees and humans.  Humans breathe in oxygen and exhale carbon dioxide, while trees breathe in carbon dioxide and exhale oxygen. There are many similarities between humans and trees. For example, let’s take the American Hardwood tree. These trees are like humans in three distinct and profound ways: Both are mostly water; both have a peak life span of approximately 80 years and both are completely unique. The most important similarity between humans and trees is that each tree, like each human, is unique and beautiful in its own way.&#xa;&#xa;People need trees. They need to see leaves from their windows, to sit in green spaces, and to play in the shade. Trees draw people out from behind walls of brick and glass. Nature restores the mental functioning in the same way that food and water restore bodies.&#xa;&#xa;Man-made environments take away from us, nature gives back. . Forests, streams, rivers, lakes, and oceans demand very little from us, though they’re still engaging, ever changing, and attention-grabbing. The difference between natural and urban landscapes is how they command our attention. While man-made landscapes bombard us with stimulation, their natural counterparts give us the chance to think as much or as little as we’d like, and the opportunity to replenish exhausted mental resource.&#xa;&#xa;Choosing Nature is always the best way to go.&#xa;&#xa;&#xa;&#xa;"/>
                <contentfragment_1070
                    cq:styleIds="[1627532710932]"
                    jcr:created="{Date}2021-07-29T22:53:57.273+05:30"
                    jcr:createdBy="admin"
                    jcr:lastModified="{Date}2021-07-29T22:55:40.903+05:30"
                    jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                    jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                    sling:resourceType="yogaholics/components/content/contentFragment"
                    displayMode="multi"
                    fragmentPath="/content/dam/yogaholics/content-fragment/11-easy-poses-for-high-blood-pressure"
                    text="                    Title                                            11 Easy Poses For High Blood Pressure            &#xa;&#xa;                        Author                                            By:Gurudev Ravishankar            &#xa;&#xa;                        Description                                             &#xa;&#xa;High blood pressure or hypertension is a serious condition that leads to heart attacks, strokes, and even death. This ‘silent killer’ is all the more dangerous because it displays no symptoms. So, the only way you can find out is by getting yourself checked regularly. The next logical step is, of course, to know how to control high blood pressure.&#xa;&#xa;Yoga and pranayama are two natural ways to control high blood pressure.&#xa;&#xa;What is hypertension or high blood pressure?&#xa;&#xa;Blood pressure is the force of blood in your arteries. The right pressure varies from person to person and needs to be regulated. Only then will your system function smoothly. The American Heart Association considers 120/80 as the standard blood pressure limit. Pre-hypertension is when your parameter is between 120/80 and 140/90. Anything above 140/90 is hypertension and is dangerous.&#xa;&#xa;What causes high blood pressure?&#xa;&#xa;Hypertension is an independent condition which means that it is not triggered by other medical conditions like diabetes, heart-related problems or kidney malfunctioning.&#xa;&#xa;Stress is a significant factor that causes hypertension. When you are stressed, your heart beats faster, and your blood vessels contract.&#xa;&#xa;Other factors such as adverse lifestyle choices including smoking, drinking, drug abuse also causes harm.&#xa;&#xa;If you do not exercise enough or are overweight, you could be heading towards hypertension.&#xa;&#xa;How to control high blood pressure&#xa;&#xa;Neither a high nor a low blood pressure is desirable; a balance is essential in the body. While healthy dietary habits contribute to maintaining balance, you cannot ignore the role played by the mind either. So, how can you harmonize the two? The answer lies in the ancient science of yoga. By regularly practising simple postures, yoga will help you combat blood pressure problems.&#xa;&#xa;Why Yoga poses for high blood pressure&#xa;&#xa;Yoga asanas involve breathing consciously and deeply while synchronizing your body movements. They can help control blood pressure naturally, primarily by relieving stress.&#xa;&#xa;Yoga asanas can soothe the nerves and help slow down an abnormal heart rate.&#xa;&#xa;Yoga helps in increasing immunity and reducing incidences of heart problems like heart attacks and strokes.&#xa;&#xa;Lack of sufficient rest is the primary reason for stress and hypertension. Yoga helps regularize sleep habits and patterns.&#xa;&#xa;Obesity can also lead to hypertension. Regular practice of yoga and an improved diet regulates body weight.&#xa;&#xa;Yoga gives positive energy to the body and mind. It makes you happier and more hopeful in life. In the long run, this helps to regulate blood pressure levels.&#xa;&#xa;The how: Yoga Poses for high blood pressure&#xa;&#xa;The following yoga asanas can help lower high blood pressure. However, it would be best to practice them under the guidance of a trained specialist.&#xa;&#xa;Yoga Poses for high blood pressure&#xa;&#xa;Shishuasana (Child Pose)&#xa;&#xa;Vajrasana (Diamond Pose)&#xa;&#xa;Paschimottanasana (Forward Bend Pose)&#xa;&#xa;Shavasana (Corpse Pose)&#xa;&#xa;Sukhasana (Easy Pose)&#xa;&#xa;Ardha Matsyendrasana (Sitting Half Spinal Twist)&#xa;&#xa;Badhakonasana (Butterfly Pose)&#xa;&#xa;Janusirsasana (One-legged Forward Bend)&#xa;&#xa;Virasana (hero pose)&#xa;&#xa;Setu Bandhasana (Bridge Pose)&#xa;&#xa;Ardha halasana (half plow pose)&#xa;&#xa;&#xa;&#xa;"/>
            </responsivegrid>
            <card_2108754793
                jcr:created="{Date}2021-07-22T18:52:13.778+05:30"
                jcr:createdBy="admin"
                jcr:lastModified="{Date}2021-07-23T09:50:19.331+05:30"
                jcr:lastModifiedBy="admin"
                jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                sling:resourceType="yogaholics/components/content/card">
                <cards jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured">
                    <item0
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        cardtitle="Hello"
                        desc="jsfjsfsdf"
                        path="/content/dam/we-retail/en/activities/hiking/hiking_3.jpg"/>
                    <item1
                        jcr:primaryType="nt:unstructured"
                        cardtitle="wfsf"
                        desc="fsf"
                        path="fdsffsdafsf"/>
                </cards>
            </card_2108754793>
        </root>
    </jcr:content>
    <healthAndWellness/>
    <yogaPostures/>
    <yogaForBeginners/>
    <wisdom/>
</jcr:root>
